Okay, so in this video
then, we are going to
cover the topic of emotional intelligence.
Now, emotional intelligence is a big
topic.
Right, so we are actually
going to be covering
emotional intelligence in a
couple of different videos.
Now, emotional intelligence is the study
of emotions, as their name suggests.
But it's basically understanding
your own emotions
and understanding,
recognizing the emotion of others.
right.
So it's recognizing your own emotions,
right?
And then plus other, you
know, people around you,
understanding their emotions,
right, recognizing their cues.
And then you adjust your behavior
accordingly.
And basically you want to minimize
conflicts, right?
So it's essentially understanding what's
going to trigger your emotions,
understanding you.
So you need to understand yourself,
right?
So whether you're happy,
whether you're sad, whether
you're angry, and how does
that impact the way you work?
How does that impact the way people see
you?
And how does that impact your work?
So do you bring your personal problems
into the workplace, for example?
So this is what emotional intelligence is
all about, right?
So understanding your own emotions.
Understand what impacts your work and
relationship with others.
And strong leaders are someone that can
always control their emotions.
Now, there's two basic components, two
major components of emotional intelligence.
These two here, personal skills and
interpersonal skills.
And we've got separate videos on each of
these.
However, just at a high level though,
just introduce these two components.
So personal skills, there's three.
three basic components of personal skills,
right, self-awareness, self-regulation,
motivation.
So self-awareness, how well you know your
emotions, what makes you happy,
what makes you sad?
It's basically understanding that and
understanding essentially
how to control them.
What ticks you off, right?
You know, what controls your mood?
And then how do you react in a certain
situation?
That's about self-awareness,
understanding your own
emotions, understanding
how do I accomplish work?
Does your mood affect your work?
So problems that you're having at home,
for example, or problems that you're
having in your personal life, is that
impacting your work, right?
You bring in that to the office.
So that's what self-awareness
is about, it's about
understanding how will
you know your emotions.
Now, once you know your emotions,
once you understand what can trigger your
emotions, then you can
regulate your emotions,
and that's what self-regulation is about.
How do you actually control your emotions?
And so, again, are you happy?
Are you sad?
Are you angry?
Is that going to control the work?
Is that going to control your work?
Does that actually affect your workplace.
Does your heart control, or rather,
does your emotions control the heart?
Does your emotions control the mind?
So is a heart controlling the mind,
a type of thing?
Right.
So, or can he separate those?
And a good leader is always one that will
be able to separate.
So, regardless of what stress they're
having at home, regardless of what stress
or problems they're having in
their personal life, you always
try to avoid to bring it,
bringing it into the work life.
So that's what self-regulation refers to.
Also, things like, how do I respond to
failure?
How do you respond to change?
How do you respond to failure?
And that's something we're going to be
talking about in a separate video.
But just remember, a leader, any kind of
leader that you've come across,
right, any leader that we're here of,
business leaders and so and so forth,
And it's not always been playing sailing
for them.
They've always had
setbacks and a good leader will
always have at some
kind of failure somewhere.
But the question is,
it's not about failing,
it's about how do you respond to failure?
If you fail in a task and you just give
up, is that being a good leader?
Or you failed, you've
dropped, you're falling
down, you pick yourself up and move along.
So that's all about self-regulation.
And then you have motivation.
A motivation is what motivates me,
right?
What motivates you?
What are the reasons for your achievement?
And everybody's motivated differently,
right?
Everyone has different motivations.
Some people are motivated by money.
Some people are motivated by affiliation.
Some people are motivated by achievement.
Everybody is motivated differently.
Some people are motivated by power.
So motivation is basically what motivates
me.
right and as I said so different people
are motivated by different needs and then
you have interpersonal skills so one of
the other components and emotional
intelligence interpersonal skills and
interpersonal skills basically relates to
others how well you relate to other people
so the two components there are social
skills and empathy right so social skills
and how well you communicate with others
but how will you influence others and
collaborate.
So how well you build relationships?
That's what social skills refers to.
A good leader is always a good
communicator or any leader, whether you
consider them a good leader or a bad
leader irrelevant.
Have you ever seen a leader, of any kind
of business leader, wherever, have you
ever seen a leader that doesn't know how
to communicate?
No, leaders always communicate.
Leaders always influence.
These are a couple of traits of a leader.
They can communicate to the audience,
right?
They can collaborate.
Leadership is all about networking and
collaboration.
And in order to network and collaborate,
you need to communicate.
You need to influence.
Again, influence does not mean force.
Influence means encouraging.
So leadership is all about building
relationships.
And that's what the social skills section
of interpersonal skills relate to and then
empathy and empathy is basically how well
you relate to others how well you
understand others how well you understand
the emotions about this essentially you
know do you understand you know your
customers do you understand your team
members do you understand you know people
that follow you it's like they all saying
you know you need to walk in someone
else's shoes right so that's what empathy
reverse too.
Okay, so these are a couple of the
components, a couple of the important
components of emotional intelligence,
right, then we're going to be covering
personal skills, interpersonal skills
separately in separate videos.